<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ludbek</title><link href="http://ludbek.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ludbek.com/feeds/all/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ludbek.com/</id><updated>2015-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Why We Stare At Eyes</title><link href="http://ludbek.com/blog/why-we-stare-at-eyes/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ludbek</name></author><id>tag:ludbek.com,2015-03-05:blog/why-we-stare-at-eyes/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we talk, see or watch someone we often stare them at their eyes. I believe there are three reasons for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the color distinction of eyes is dominant compared to other parts of the face&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our eyes have natural tendency of focusing at spots with greater color distinction. They either focus at too dark or at too light. Next time you focus on something evaluate how distinct it is from its surrounding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eyes have movement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eyes are good at spotting changes. They easily get distracted to a movement. Eyes and lips are the two parts that can move. That is why we tend to focus on eyes and lips when we talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;focusing at an eye our brain can get symmetry of entire face&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would rather write an article on this topic in more generic approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="eye"></category><category term="pyschology"></category></entry><entry><title>Everyone Is Happy Inside</title><link href="http://ludbek.com/blog/every-one-is-happy-inside/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ludbek</name></author><id>tag:ludbek.com,2015-02-18:blog/every-one-is-happy-inside/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="happy skulls" src="http://ludbek.com/images/happySkulls.jpg" /&gt;
image source &lt;a href="http://liquid-venom.deviantart.com/art/Skull-Reference-Sheet-469763341"&gt;liquid venom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bullshit"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>The Fourth Law For Robots</title><link href="http://ludbek.com/blog/the-fourth-law-for-robots/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ludbek</name></author><id>tag:ludbek.com,2013-10-18:blog/the-fourth-law-for-robots/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Isaac Asimov devised &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Laws_of_Robotics"&gt;3 laws of robotics&lt;/a&gt;. According to him:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A robot must obey the orders given to it by human beings, except where such orders would conflict with the First Law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection does not conflict with the First or Second Law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems these laws prevent humans from being harmed by their own creation. But it has a shortcoming. We are creating all sorts of robots. Some of them are intelligent. In future they will create their own version of Artificial Intelligence i.e robots creating intelligent robots. They might or might not pass the 3 laws to their creation. Some might argue that not passing the laws violates the first law. Yes it would if the AI realizes that. But there is no such thing as absolute intelligence. Some might realize it some might not. These 3rd generation of intelligence without the 3 laws might hurt humans as there is nothing telling them not to. So, we need the 4th law, the law of inheritance. Which states:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;A robot should pass all these laws to the robot it creates.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Finally, the humans are safe. Thanks to the the 4th law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ai"></category><category term="robot"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World !!!</title><link href="http://ludbek.com/blog/hello-world/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>ludbek</name></author><id>tag:ludbek.com,2013-10-17:blog/hello-world/</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>